WWW.MY-SUBS.COM
JONATHAN: 55 days ago,
24 Australians began
the adventure of a lifetime...
..playing the world's greatest game.
Now, just three remain.
And tonight,
one will be crowned Sole Survivor.
Advertising producer Peter...
Peter wins immunity!
..quietly playing his game
under the radar.
It's not about the biggest move,
I think it's about the best move.
Rodeo-riding mother Tara.
Boom!
She went from outsider to the finale
thanks to her strong social game.
I ain't no stay-at-home mum.
I'm a frickin' barrel racer.
Or flight attendant Jericho,
playing hard
beneath the smiling exterior.
JERICHO: There will be bloodshed.
If it is me, then I hope that
I drag someone with me down to hell.
(LAUGHS)
Last time...
Michelle's in the water.
..Peter won immunity...
Does he have it? Yes!
..and had Jericho in his sights.
And I was like, "What, what?!
What's happening here?"
Tara used her vote to split the numbers.
At deadlock at the final four
means Michelle and Jericho will now
compete in a fire-making challenge.
Survivors, ready? Go.
Jericho and Michelle fought for
their lives in a race to make fire.
Michelle is not giving up.
Jericho wins this challenge.
Tonight, the challenge to end them all.
The ultimate test
of exhausted bodies and minds.
Let go of that idol
and you could be letting go
of your place in the game.
Who will outwit,
outplay and outlast the others
to win the $500,000
and the title of Sole Survivor?
JERICHO: To know that there's
two days left - that's 48 hours -
and that there's three of us left.
It just feels incredible to know
that we are this close
to the finish line.
To get there to the end...
..I just need to win
the final Immunity Challenge.
It's gonna be one helluva fight.
To see all the torches
that represented all the people that
have gone through this whole game,
is so surreal.
It makes me feel like I do deserve
to be in the final three.
And those other players tried
but I've outlasted them.
Joan! It's been a long time.
I didn't meet Joan.
- Me either.
- I did.
She was the first person that would
put her hand up for the puzzle.
I think she knew that it could make
her a hero or send her packing.
Adam. I feel like he gave
away his cards a little too early.
I want to find the idol.
You can come and have a look for it,
if you want to play with me.
TARA: Oh, Kate.
This player, good at challenges.
- Yay!
- Good job, Kate!
- Mr. Character himself.
- The soul of the tribe.
Tarzan.
TARZAN: But I happen to be in a game
where you're supposed to draw alliances.
Well, maybe being a friend to
somebody might make a stronger one.
Being true to myself,
for me, was everything.
God, I love this game!
Oh, my favourite!
- Aimee!
- Aimee.
She looked like a hairdresser
and, in fact, she was a plumber.
Spewin'!
Sam was a pocket rocket
in our challenges.
Her downfall, though, was Mark.
MARK: Sam and I, we're a close pair.
If I met her on the outside,
I'd definitely be keen on her.
They were just like a power pair and
so we had to send Mark and Sam home.
- Jacqui!
- Oh, Jacqui.
JACQUI: It's like a game
of Monopoly, you know?
You can be playing
with your best friend,
and as soon as you hit Mayfair,
you just buy it
and then you put hotels on it
and wipe her out.
- Kent.
- My strategy is find the dickhead.
If you look around
and you can't find the dickhead,
it's you and you're in real trouble.
Oh, here's one - AK.
I will say that he played a great
game. But look where it got him.
It's a chicken idol. Look at it -
it's in the shape of a chicken.
I was completely on the outs
from the start of this.
I turned it round. I gained trust.
But that swap cost me.
- Oh, we got AK!
- Yeah!
I just want to be remembered
as the player that played big.
JERICHO: Ben 10. He was
the youngest contestant.
Wow.
Odette. She'd say what she wanted
to say and she would move on.
- Our first jury member.
- Jarrad!
Oh, an incredibly guy.
One of my closest allies in this game.
JARRAD: Up until the merge,
I was in control.
Come the merge,
that control has slipped away.
PETER: I actually
really liked Anneliese.
Higher! Higher!
We went to Exile together,
so we shared this moment that no-one
else in the game can experience.
Master Hen Zen.
Henry!
- JONATHAN: Henry takes it for Asaga!
- (ALL CHEER)
He had the charisma, the charm.
Whoo!
People fell under Henry's spell.
HENRY: First thing I said was
a lie - I'm a yoga instructor.
Namaste.
I was throwing challenges,
I was building multiple alliances.
I want to be remembered as the guy
that absolutely played the game
from day one.
PETER: Tessa.
She was logical, she was smart.
I felt like I not only lost
a player in the game
but actually like a true friend
when Tess went home.
JERICHO: Whoa, Sarah!
The model that can start a fire
and doesn't mind to get dirty.
Mm!
- Luke.
- Oh, Lukey!
Oh!
Yeah, boy!
- Ra!
- (SQUEALS)
- Oh, (BLEEP).
- Got ya.
Got ya!
JERICHO: I couldn't have had
another brother in this game
other than Luke.
He was probably my other half.
LUKE: I'm here to stir the pot,
make sure everyone's on their toes.
I'm creeping.
You can't be sitting there, walking
around, thinking you're the boss.
I'm the boss!
PETER: Ziggy.
She was a fierce competitor.
A powerhouse in the challenges.
Ziggy wins first individual immunity.
Oh, my Locky.
I don't know if I could've got
this far, really, without him.
You know, the guy won three
immunity challenges in a row.
Yeah!
Oh, I love you, Locky.
- Mish!
- Michelle.
On the barge she had this beautiful
dress on and she was freezing
and we were all thinking,
"She won't last long."
JONATHAN: Michelle takes
individual immunity!
JERICHO: She wanted to come out of
this game with fireworks
and she did.
TARA: For a minute there, I thought,
"My name isn't on any of these torches
"and that's because
I'm still here."
And it made me feel
a little bit more confident
to lead into that
final Immunity Challenge.
Oh, my gosh.
It's epic.
Even though I haven't won
a single challenge,
I feel this one is, more than ever,
the important one.
This is the finale.
This is the one that gives you the power
to choose who you want to take
to the final two.
So this one is like...
the golden buckle in barrel racing.
Come on in, guys.
PETER: Last night, I could see that
the Immunity Necklace
was my lifeline in this game.
And I think it will be my lifeline
again for the next Tribal.
The way I see it is that
this challenge is do or die.
And... I need to do
because I don't want to die.
This is it, guys.
You ready to get to your final
Immunity Challenge?
- Yes!
- Yep.
First things first.
Peter, need to take it back.
Thank you.
For the last time,
immunity is back up for grabs.
OK, today's challenge
may look a little familiar.
That's because we did it
here last year...
..and it turned out to be
the toughest challenge in the game.
This year, it may even be
a little tougher.
Right now it's late afternoon,
but soon that sun's going to set.
And you'll be competing at night.
Oh!
You're gonna get wet and you'll
have no sun to keep you warm.
You'll hear the waves
but you won't see them coming.
This is the challenge where Kristie
made her mark in Survivor.
Now it's time to make yours.
Alright, you know how this works.
You're gonna stand with both feet
on narrow pedestals
with one hand on the idol.
If at any stage you break contact
at any of those three points,
if your free hand touches the idol
or the stand that it's sitting on...
..you're out of the challenge.
Last person left standing wins immunity
and a spot in the final two,
guaranteed a 50% chance
of winning $500,000
and the title of Sole Survivor.
Alright, let's draw for spots
and get started.
- Good luck. Good luck, Peter.
- Good luck.
Alright... assume the position.
For immunity
and a spot in the final two,
this challenge is now on.
This is a pretty simple challenge,
this one.
Just need to hang on as long as you can.
It's not a very comfortable position.
There's not much to balance on
on those pedestals.
Soon that discomfort
will turn into pain.
And then it becomes about
pain management.
Mind over matter at that point.
So much of this challenge
is really just psychological.
Convincing yourself
that you can keep going.
This is what Survivor's about.
You gotta dig deep if you want it.
Here we go.
That swell's starting to come up.
And we're not even mid tide yet.
That's gonna be the first of many...
..I'm guessing.
You guys have been
out here for 30 minutes.
Tara, the sun's about to set.
You're gonna be doing this
challenge at night.
How do you feel about that?
When I can see the waves come,
I can sort of duck my head down.
At night-time,
a wave could hit you in the face
and you could just lose balance.
So this has upped the ante
with doing it in the dark,
that's for sure.
What about you, Peter. Are you
concerned, with your back to ocean?
If it's dark, my back to the ocean
doesn't make a difference, so... no.
We've had a cyclone, we've had storms.
That's why you've just got to
be able to tough it out.
- Yeah.
- Is that your mantra today?
"Tough it out"?
Yep, got to tough it out.
I like it.
Well, the sun has well and truly gone.
This is the last of the light.
Night's about to fall.
I hope you're all prepared for the wet,
the cold, wind and the dark.
This is where the real challenge begins.
Oh, my God.
JERICHO: Whoa.
Wow!
- You guys all get that?
- Yep, right in the face.
One hour, guys.
How's everyone feeling?
- JERICHO: Good.
- PETER: Good.
Shit.
I'll be honest.
Thank you, Tara.
Everyone else is lying to me, right?
JERICHO: Whoo...
It is jet-black out here.
You really cannot see
what's going on with the surf.
- You can hear them, but
you can't see 'em. - Yep.
You don't know which one's gonna hit.
- Whoa.
- Ahh!
Oh, my God.
You're moving your feet around a
lot, Jericho. Are they getting sore?
They're good, actually. I'm fine.
Or am I lying?! (LAUGHS)
You'll never know.
So, game face is definitely
a strategy for you?
Yeah.
Well, I hope you're comfortable
because you have been out here
for 90 minutes.
Peter, how would it feel to make it
to the final two, on Day 55?
As far as you can go?
It honestly would be a dream come true.
I've loved Survivor
for a really long time
and to win would be, you know,
the whole package.
But the only way you can
make that dream official right now
is to win this challenge.
So, that's what I've got to
focus on doing.
Guys, you've been out here
for two hours now.
Don't give up now.
Very different pictures here.
Jericho looking very solid.
Peter, head down, in the zone.
Tara, moving around a lot, trying
to find something comfortable.
The muscles must be cramping now.
Tara, what do you think has got you
this far in the game?
Yeah, I was just being me.
I'm a stay-at-home mum, you know?
So...
Oh, no, don't get me wrong.
I love my job, but...
..some of these guys are,
you know...
Like, we had Ziggy, the Olympian,
and Locky jumps off buildings and...
- Jarrad's an incredible photographer.
- Yeah.
- Tessa's a doctor. There's so many
amazing people. - That's right.
That's true, and everyone has a shot
in this game.
Just... it's just...
Yeah, I just feel very blessed.
But...
..I just don't want to
disappoint anyone.
I don't want to
disappoint myself. So...
Yeah.
Tara, you seem to be getting
quite emotional.
- What's going on for you?
- Oh, I'm just trying to pull it in.
Pull it all together, you know?
My emotions are starting to get over me
and I'm really trying hard
to just... bear down.
But... it's starting to hurt and...
..I just don't want to feel like
I don't...
..feel like I'm not
meant to be here, but I am.
But... I just can't...
I'm just trying my hardest, that's all.
I'm trying really hard.
Hey, you're final three.
You totally deserve to be here.
JERICHO: You're doing so well, Tara.
(CRIES) I know. I'm trying!
- PETER: You're doing amazing, Tara.
- I really am trying!
My legs aren't holding me anymore.
PETER: You got this Tara.
Don't give up.
Do your best, Tara.
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
Tara, you can cry all you want
but just keep your hand on that idol
and your feet on the pedestals.
There's one thing about Survivor
that I keep on saying, again and again.
Just never give up.
Nup.
I know all three of you
want to win this challenge.
And that necklace has
some serious power tonight.
Let go of that idol
and you could be letting go of
your place in the game.
(GROANS)
The waves really pounding in now.
Ohhhh...
Talk.
I don't know if I can talk now
because I... it's bad.
What's the different names again?
So, a stallion is...?
A st...
A stallion is a male horse.
A mare is a female horse.
A filly is a young female horse
and colt is a young male horse.
JERICHO: A colt?
C-O-L-T?
(GASPS AND CHUCKLES)
I know what you're do...
It's good. Keep trying.
I'm trying, eh? I'm trying to talk.
Um...
PETER: Oh... God.
You're doing amazing, Tara.
Tara looks like
she's in serious pain now.
Really starting to wobble.
Ooh.
Tara almost loses her balance.
Nice recovery.
Good job, Tara.
You've been out here for 53 days.
That is a long time with not much
food, not much sleep...
Incredibly exhausting.
How much is left in the tank
for this final challenge?
And she's had enough.
She's stepping out of the challenge.
(GROANS)
Two hours and 55 minutes.
- (GROANS)
- JERICHO: Wow, almost three.
Almost three hours, Tara.
Yep.
Your family's gonna be
very proud of you.
I hope so.
You've done incredibly well.
- You did so well, Tara.
- You did great, Tara.
Alright, here we go.
- Ready?
- Yep.
Up you hop.
So, now we're down to two.
Peter and Jericho...
..battling it out for that necklace.
Who's gonna be the last one standing?
Wow!
Just as Tara steps off,
the ocean gets really angry.
We're not even at high tide yet.
Jericho...
..if Peter wins,
are you worried you could be going home?
Yeah.
Peter...
- Yep.
- ..if Jericho wins,
are you worried that
you could be going home?
Absolutely, yes.
Well, you guys have now been
out here for three and a half hours.
How much longer do you think
you've got in you?
Um, till the morning.
- Till the morning?
- Yeah.
Wow.
Peter, is that a little bit
of a concern?
No, I'll match that if I have to.
Looks like we might be here for a while.
You guys are just getting smashed now.
The wind is definitely picking up.
That's not gonna help, with wet clothes.
Another massive wave pounds them both.
Damn.
Every wave now just cuts to the bone.
The wind kicking up.
Soaked to the core.
Really starting to shake with the cold.
There's no way to increase
your body temperature
when you're stuck in one position
like that.
It's all about the psychology now.
"How long can I last?"...
..versus "How long can they last?"
It's a waiting game now.
Both boys determined
to give it everything they've got.
Reaching to the bottom of the tank.
Trying to find that inner strength
to keep going.
Who's gonna reach
the end of their limit?
(PETER GROANS)
Jonathan?
Can I have a hand getting down, please?
You want to step down?
Alright.
After five and a quarter hours,
Peter no longer can stand up.
Jericho wins the final immunity.
Let's rock!
You're right, you're right,
you're right.
Just take your time.
Oh! Oh, ma...
Sit down for a bit, babe.
Sit down for a little bit.
I don't cry. I don't cry.
You alright?
That was a massive, massive effort.
(JERICHO SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
Peter, come here, come here. Bro...
You made me fight for my life!
You have gained my respect, my bro.
Man, I'm so proud of you.
Peter, how you feeling?
Think you can walk?
I'm OK.
Sit and... sit and talk.
Take this off, my bro,
'cause it's really damp.
We proved to everybody that we
deserve to be in the final three.
No-one can tell us and devalue
what we've achieved.
Yeah?
(ALL SCREAM)
(LAUGHS) What?!
God!
JONATHAN: Peter and Tara,
that was a massive effort
but, Jericho, come on over.
- Good work, Jer.
- Well and truly earned this.
After five hours...
..and 13 minutes.
First Individual Immunity win
in the final challenge.
Congratulations.
You are safe, can not be voted out.
Guaranteed a spot in the final two,
where you will get a chance
to plead your case to the jury.
But before we get to that...
..tomorrow night at Tribal Council,
you have a big decision to make.
Your vote will decide
who will join you in the final two
and who will become
the final member of the jury.
It's a lot to think about. Go back
to camp, get a good night's sleep.
I'll see you guys tomorrow
at Tribal Council.
- Alright. Well done. Congratulations.
- Thank you.
ALL: Thanks, Jonathan.
TARA: Well done, Jer.
JERICHO: This is the biggest
decision of my entire life.
Tonight is deciding
the person that will sit next to me
and plead their case against mine
for that Sole Survivor title
and that $500,000.
It's crazy.
You can weigh up the two options
that I have -
they're both very different people.
It's like trying to decide
apples and oranges.
And I could possibly be putting the
wrong person in the finals with me
and giving someone else $500,000.
It is the biggest,
most terrifying position to be in
that I have to make a decision
like that.
We'll now bring in
the members of our jury.
Jarrad, Anneliese, Henry, Sarah...
..Luke, Ziggy, Locky
and Michelle, voted out
at the last Tribal Council.
Well, first of all,
I want to say that was an epic
battle in the final challenge.
Massive effort from everyone.
Well done.
And just to catch up the jury.
So, the final challenge
was the same as last year
except we did it at night,
which added a whole level
of difficulty unto itself.
Tara lasted almost three hours.
The boys went for an impressive
five hours and 13 minutes
before Peter stepped off.
- Well done.
- Good job.
So, Jericho,
you finally got your wish -
first Individual Immunity win
in the final challenge.
How does that feel?
The Survivor gods were telling me,
"Patience
and you will get your wish."
And it was quite of a battle.
I didn't just get it easily,
I had to earn it.
And I have mad respect
for the two of them.
It was a good fight.
Well, you hold all the power tonight.
Is it more important to you
to take someone you can beat
or someone who you think will put up
a good fight in the final two?
It's not about who's an easy win.
It's more so who deserves
to be sitting next to me
and how they should stand against me
in the final two.
That's how I look at it.
Tara, why should Jericho
not take Peter to the end?
I still feel strongly
that Jeri and I are both lovable
and social characters in the game
and we take every move seriously.
And, you know, that's why I feel
that if he was to take Peter,
the jury would see that as
he's just taken the easy ride out.
- My turn?
- Yeah.
Firstly, I couldn't disagree more. I
do not think I am the easy ride out.
I think Jericho
has played a really good game.
And I believe that the jury
would respect someone who stuck
to their word in taking big plays.
And I believe
I am a big player in this game.
I believe I've really had to
fight my way through.
And I've worked with a lot of people
and I've worked individually.
And I believe that
if he does take Tara to the end,
when there is very likely
a consensus from the jury
that Tara is the weaker player,
then he's potentially
undermining his own game,
whereby he's not taking risks
and he's not making a big move
in taking someone like me
who's played a really good game
to the end.
Sorry.
But, like, you had the opportunity.
- You owned this necklace...
- Yeah.
..three days ago.
And you went around to me and Michelle
and you were like, "Just pick
Jericho. Jericho's the easy vote."
And you're trying to sit here and
tell me that you've taken huge risk.
It was the last opportunity
to prove to the jury
that you've got some sort of balls
to go ahead and battle
for that spot that you want.
I took that opportunity
and hold on to it.
And I didn't let it go.
I make logical decisions in this game.
And I weighed up
what the jury was thinking
and I also weighed up
that the final challenge
was most likely going to be physical
and for my game, the most logical
decision and the smartest option
was honestly to take out Jericho.
Alright. Well, I'm going to give you
guys a final pitch.
Peter, why should Jericho
take you to the end?
Jericho, I believe
I have played a really good game.
The jury, because they are
made of such big game players,
they want to see someone
who's played a strong game
in the final with Jericho.
So, I believe not taking me
will undermine Jericho's game
because he is based on playing
big risks and making big moves.
And if you're taking an easier option,
and I'm sorry, Tara,
but I do believe
you are the easier option tonight...
..because you did spend
a lot of time in Locky's shadow.
I don't believe all of your moves
have been logical in this game.
I believe if you don't take me,
then the jury will consider that
as a negative.
OK. So, Tara, why should Jericho
take you to the end?
In my defence,
I could be classed as an underdog
or I could be classed as a weak player.
But you know what? Bring it on.
Because if you want a fight,
then bring me.
You take Petey and it will be
a bit of a disrespect to the game.
- That's what I'm saying.
- Wow.
I just want to say, I disagree
entirely with that last statement.
Well, of course you disagree.
It's my time to pitch.
You just had a pitch.
- Now it's my time to pitch.
- Sorry. I thought you were finished.
You disagree.
Of course you disagree.
I'm a strong player and I feel
that at the end of the day,
if you wanted to have a fight
and battle it out
and prove
that you are the Sole Survivor,
then I'll be sitting next to you.
OK. So, this is how
it's going to work.
Peter and Tara,
you can't vote for yourself,
you can't vote for Jericho, so you
can only vote for each other,
which means that your votes
cancel each other out.
So, Jericho, ultimately you decide
who's going to leave this game
and be the final member of the jury.
- Are you ready?
- Oh, I'm ready.
Jericho, it's time to vote.
I'll go get the vote.
Once the vote is read
the decision is final,
the person voted out
will be asked to leave
the Tribal Council area immediately.
I'll read the vote.
22nd person voted out
from Australian Survivor,
final member of our jury...
..Peter.
You need to bring me your torch.
Congratulations.
And good luck, you guys.
And stay up, you guys,
we're hanging out tonight.
Peter, the tribe has spoken.
- (LOCKY CHUCKLES)
- Bring it in.
- Time to go.
- See you, Peter.
- Bye, Petey.
- Well done.
Congratulations.
Holy crap.
Day 55.
Yeah.
Jericho and Tara, congratulations.
You are the final two. You've done
everything you can in this game.
And now it's going to be up to them.
Oh, my God.
So go home, get some sleep
and think about
how you're going to convince them
that you deserve the $500,000.
- Grab your torches, head on out.
- JERICHO: Wow.
TARA: Holy crap.
I took you because you really
deserve it more than he does.
JERICHO: Good morning, Vietnam!
TARA: Hello,
day fifty-frickin'-five.
We were destined to be here at day 55.
55 days on this island.
Aaahhh!
I could win half a million!
What the heck? I'm just
a flight attendant from Melbourne.
I have been dreaming of this moment,
to know that I have a shot
in winning Survivor.
To me, I feel like dreams can come true.
It's starting to clear up
into a nice day.
The last thing I need to do
is convince the jury tonight
that I am worthy of that title
of Sole Survivor.
(BOTH SQUEAL WITH EXCITEMENT)
BOTH: "Congratulations.
"You have made it to day 55.
"Tonight you face
your last Tribal Council.
"To help you prepare, breakfast
is provided in the crate below!"
Oh, my goodness!
Ohhh!
For me, there is no option
apart from winning this.
Back in the Philippines,
my parents weren't wealthy.
In fact, we lived in a shelter that
just was able to withstand the rain.
Let's cook some food!
The reason why I stand here
is because they worked
blood, sweat and tears for me
and so I owe it to them.
Holy moly.
Are you kidding me?
Let's enjoy it sizzle.
I feel like they deserve everything
and I want to be the person
that can finally provide for them
just as much as they provided for me.
(POP!)
Yay! 55 days!
55 days.
- Congratulations.
- Congratulations, babe.
Cheers to...
..outlasting every single contestant
in this game,
and doing an amazing job at it.
Mmm! Mm.
What a way to finish
a really tough game.
I really want that title
because I feel that I deserve it
more than anyone in this game.
I'll be honest,
I did second prioritise
making friends in this game.
Oh.
People underestimated me.
People thought that
I was this angelic boy, when really,
I was a wolf in sheep's clothing.
I always made sure that resources
were used wisely.
I had Luke.
He was my best friend
and we conquered Asaga together.
Then I had the jar of cookies
and I used it to build an army.
I placed certain people in
the front line to fight my battles,
to act as shields.
They were the ones that got taken down,
with my name never been written down
until 52 days later.
And that is why
I guaranteed myself a spot
to plead my case in front of the jury.
I am going to make sure that
they give me that crown tonight,
because I deserve it.
One, two, three.
If I ever met Jericho
in the outside world,
it would probably be more of just
a "hi, hi, see ya later."
- Whoo!
The fact is,
we have a great relationship
and we could even have a good
friendship outside the game.
2017 Sole Survivor! Whoo!
- What!? No, you're not!
- (SQUEALS)
But tonight at Tribal Council,
I'll be leaving the friendship
at the door.
Jeri and I will be going in
as fierce competitors.
Look at this.
This is the home we've been
living in for the last 55 days.
I look at it and I go, "Jericho
has been living in this beach
"since day one."
How cool is it even
that I'm going to prove to you
that you shouldn't have arrived
in this game?
- Oh-hoo!
- (LAUGHS)
Jericho made a mistake
taking me to the final two.
He's looking at me as
not a big threat when I will be.
I survived by getting booted out
of Samatau, headed to Exile Beach,
then I had to come here to Asaga,
form new relationships and build trust,
make it to the merge,
and Jericho has never left Asaga.
- Bye, beach!
But then on top of that,
I can say that I have survived
21 Tribal Councils
and Jeri only got
his name written down once.
He definitely had it easy.
- I'm really emotional.
- Same.
(LAUGHS)
I don't really...
I don't know if I want to go.
I just feel like we're saying
goodbye to our home.
Half a million dollars -
it sets up my family.
I have three growing boys
and with Mum living with us as well,
it'd be nice to get her a little
place where she can call home.
So I would do anything
to win that money.
Oh, man.
I'm gonna miss this place.
What a journey.
You. Ladies first.
Thanks.
Bye-bye.
It's nerve racking to go into
the last Tribal Council
knowing that the person
that I chose to sit next to
is the person that I'm battling it
out for that title of Sole Survivor.
There is a big possibility that Tara
could run away with the money
and that I made the wrong decision
and that I should have taken Peter
instead of Tara.
But the decision I make
is a decision I have to own
and if it's Tara that wins it,
then the only person to blame is me.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
I'll now bring in
the members of our jury.
Jarrad,
Anneliese,
Henry,
Sarah,
Luke,
Ziggy,
Locky,
Michelle,
Peter, voted out
in the last Tribal Council.
So here we are, day 55,
final Tribal Council.
Congratulations.
JERICHO: Thank you.
Jericho, Tara, you two have gone
as far as you can go in this game,
and tonight the power now shifts
to the jury.
Nine people you've had a hand -
either directly or indirectly -
voting out from this game
will now decide
which of you two deserves
the title of Sole Survivor
and the half a million dollars
that goes with it.
Now, up until this point,
they've been pretty much quiet.
They're gonna have an opportunity
tonight to address you.
They can ask anything
and you can answer however you want.
But remember,
whatever you say to the jury
could make or break your game.
So this is how it's gonna work.
You will each make an opening statement.
This is your chance to pitch to the jury
why you deserve to win this game.
Then, one by one, they'll address you.
Finally, they'll go to vote
to decide who will win this game.
You ready?
Ready.
Yep. Let's do it.
Tara, you're up.
Hi, guys. Um...
I guess for myself, it was
so hard going against you guys,
I have to say straight off the bat.
It was scary.
Sitting on that barge on day one,
looking around, I was petrified.
Locky's arms were bigger than my legs,
so I knew I had some work to do
and I knew my game plan,
I would have to be a social player.
I spoke to everyone.
I knew I could draw people in,
that it was a way of keeping you guys in
that got me to where I am here today.
You've got to remember, yes,
this is a game,
but I'm a human being
and I have emotions.
When I moved over to Asaga,
I went from the highest high
of being in a great alliance
to the lowest low of feeling like
nobody wants you
and you're pretty well rejected.
So I promised myself I wasn't
just gonna grab on to, like,
two or three people.
I was gonna spread my wings,
making sure I have alliances with
every member in the Asaga group,
so if I ever was in a bottom
of an alliance,
I knew I had a plan A, a plan B
and even a plain C.
When we hit the merge,
I knew straightaway
I was always gonna stick with Locky.
A lot of you guys see Locky as my shield
and I am first to admit
that he was my shield.
I needed someone big and mighty
to get me through
the next couple of Tribals,
so I was happy to tag along.
So then with all that said,
there had to come a time
to take out Locky.
It was my chance to prove
that I have had a shield
but the shield now needs to go and
I have to start using my own armour.
So then day 50, day 51 came,
we were getting close to top three.
I could have went the easy way out
with Petey and Michelle,
but the person I knew
that deserved to be at least
battling out for the top three
and not just getting an easy vote
was Jeri,
and what better way than to fight
with a fire challenge?
All I can say now is,
I feel tonight that this is the spot
that I deserve,
and I just hope I've played
a big enough game
that the jury will respect.
Jericho.
Over to you.
First and foremost,
I just want to thank you all,
to have been a part of this game.
I feel that every single one of you
played an amazing game.
Now. To open the Book of Jericho
that needs to be revealed.
I had one goal that was in my mind
and that was that if I can convince
and make anyone believe that I was
this saint, kind-hearted Jericho,
that would never hurt anybody,
then I was already winning.
At some stage in this game,
everyone really thought that
I was this lovable guy and that
you could find a friend in me.
And friendship was there,
but at the same time,
I was willing to blindside
every single one of you
when I felt it was most important
and useful to me.
But if I wanted to get further
into the game,
I knew that I needed to have people
to use as shields,
so I had the jar of cookies.
With these cookies, I decided
I would take Luke and I told him,
"You are the person that
I feel like I can trust."
Then I told Henry.
I then told Sarah.
I told every single one of those
three different stories
to make them feel special
and so when they had started to feel
like they find loyalty in me,
I was like, great.
I have three shields that I can use.
All I needed was that
they get to the merge.
One thing that I can tell you is
that everything that I did
I can say that they were my moves
and I'm not going to try
and hide that away.
I feel that, to respect this game
is to make risky moves
and make sure that they were big moves,
and I feel that every player here
see that these big moves
is how you respect this thing
that we call Survivor.
You know, I stood in front of you
and won three individual challenges.
I won the immunity challenge
that was most important,
that guaranteed me a spot
in the final two.
I won an individual challenge which
proved to you that I can make a fire
and I gained an advantage that
refined this whole entire jury
to be in my favour.
They were game changing moves.
And that's why I am sitting here
and I came up on top.
Alright, jury, you've heard
from both Tara and Jericho.
Now it's gonna be your turn.
Ask your questions wisely,
get everything you need to make that
half million dollar decision.
Alright, jury, you've heard
from both Tara and Jericho.
Now it's gonna be your turn.
Michelle, you're first up.
Congratulations, first of all.
You're both sitting there.
The question I've gotta ask is -
tell me the biggest move
you made in the game.
I want one that you yourself
have orchestrated.
So, Tara, I'm gonna let you go first.
Trying to get Locky out.
Around day 40 I went up to Luke
and Jericho and I said, "I'm ready.
"If you guys want to come on board,
I'm ready to take out Locky."
The reason why I wanted
to get Locky out was
I wanted to allow myself at least
15 days of proving that, yes,
I used him as a shield
and now I'm on my own.
Now, we weren't expected
that he was gonna keep winning
Immunity Necklaces, so...
..I couldn't get him out
until day 49.
Jericho.
I believe my biggest move was
when I had my moral dilemma.
I decided I wanted to make this
jar of cookies
just as powerful as an idol,
and so I decided to take
three people that
I saw in Asaga were
the most crucial people,
and they will be the people that
I feel that I could take with me
to use as shields.
I told every single one of
those three different stories
to make them feel special and wanted
and know that their alliance
was basically to me.
That's why I've got myself further
in the game, because I had shields,
and I also felt like I didn't float
because I made this coalition
on my own and they didn't know that.
OK. Good luck, guys.
Anneliese, you're up.
- Hi, Anneliese.
- Hi, guys.
First and foremost,
huge congratulations.
I'm so happy for you that the
two of you are sitting here.
Jeri, when I came over to Asaga,
the perception that I had of things
was that you were working
very closely with Luke
and that you were maybe
even riding Luke's coat-tails
a little bit.
But I want to give you
a right of reply -
a way to counteract the things
that I've been thinking.
Yeah, I believe that people
will perceive me as the person
that rode Luke's coat-tails,
but I look at it as Santa Claus.
You ride the sleigh,
but I'm the one with the whip.
There were times where he would try
and tell me what to do
and I'd say, "No, that's not happening
"'cause that's not logical."
Like, I had the whip
and he was the reindeer.
(LAUGHS)
OK.
- Tara.
- Yes.
If I were to put you
and Jericho on a pedestal,
Jericho would be a little higher
than you at this point in time.
What I want to know is how and why
it's strategic to sit
next to Jericho here.
How does that benefit
your own personal game play.
I wanted to fight for my spot
and I wanted to go against
someone that out of the four of us
deserved to be battling it out
for the top three.
I knew he was good at challenges -
we had one more challenge to go -
so I knew it was going to be
between him and Petey,
and I was hoping it was going to be
Jericho
that won the Immunity Necklace.
Once I knew that necklace was his
I was hoping that because I did
help him get to the fire challenge
he would take me.
Thank you, both of you.
I want to let you know that my mind
is open and I'm willing to listen to
anything that you guys
have to say tonight.
BOTH: Thank you.
Locky, you're next.
Congratulations, guys.
55 days, that's amazing.
- Tara.
- Yeah.
I'm super-proud of you
planning to get me out.
Oh, good.
I knew it was coming and, like,
I'm not bitter or anything about it.
I'm super-proud for you
that you did it.
Jericho, my question to you was, the
day we went out swimming and stuff,
like, to me that was
a pure, genuine moment.
And I just wanted to know -
was that genuine to you
or was that just game play?
That was probably one of the biggest
highlights of this entire game.
Oh, awesome.
The minute you left, I spoke to Tara
and I really said that I truly found
somebody that I could actually hang
out with outside of this game.
I saw the Locky that
wasn't playing the game.
I'm very proud of both of you. Well
done, guys. Thank you very much.
- Thanks, Locky.
- Thank you.
Ziggy, it's your turn.
Congratulations.
I know we're all super-jealous
that it's not us sitting there,
but you did outlast us all,
so hat off to you both.
My question is to both of you.
I'll let Jericho go first.
So, Jericho, why do you think
Tara should be the Sole Survivor?
- Oh, that's a good one.
- That's a good one.
I think Tara has evolved.
Originally she acted on emotions
and definitely wore
her heart on her sleeve.
Then the second half of this game
she started to change it up,
she started realising that if she
wants to get far into this game,
she has to start making big moves
and risky ones
and controversial ones.
She just put herself on the line
and it was, like, mad respect.
And that's why I think she deserves
to be here and be a Sole Survivor.
Alright, Tara, why do you think
Jericho should be the Sole Survivor?
The strategising aside,
the fella is 159cm?
Mm.
And he drags logs that are twice his
size from the one end of the beach
to the other and he makes sure
that fire is always going.
He makes sure that
we've always got food, comfort.
When there was 12 of us in the hut,
he was the one that was sleeping at
the bottom of our feet like a dog,
because he knew there was no room.
Jericho's heart has got him
where he is today,
and this is why he deserves to be here.
- Alright, cool. Well, congrats, guys.
- BOTH: Thanks, Ziggy.
I'm sweating.
Jarrad, you're up.
Now, I'm sure you guys know, I've
been on the jury for a long time.
(ALL LAUGH)
I have had to sit there listening
to how great everybody's game is
and how everything was
everybody else's fault,
and all the amazing players
are sitting here.
But that's it, we are sitting here
and you two are the ones
that are still in the game,
so, Tara and Jericho, well done.
BOTH: Thank you.
Now, one of you will
walk away the winner,
one of you will unfortunately
join the ranks of us
and walk away with nothing.
Let's say, Jericho,
you walk away with nothing.
Let's say you lose tonight. If you
lose tonight, where did it go wrong?
I believe that my mistake
that could cost me
the whole, entire game
was to send home Tessa off the jury.
I don't know exactly what
she would have done at the jury,
but Tessa could have
potentially been the person
that could have vouched for me.
And the thing is, I won't know...
..because I have taken her out.
I do have some final words for you,
Jericho.
Yeah, sure.
I came to you after the merge,
we discussed who
we would vote for that night
and we would send a message
to each other
with an underline to
show our trust was there.
Now, you voted for me that night,
and to add salt to the wound
you underlined my name.
Now, Jericho...
..what goes around comes around.
And when I go up to write tonight...
..I'm gonna be sending a message
to you with an underline as well.
Cheers, guys.
Holy shit-balls, that was good.
Sarah, it's your turn.
Well, I'm a little bit nervous.
Firstly, congratulations
to the both of you.
This is an amazing achievement.
So, in saying that, Jericho,
the thing is,
your game seems to be panicked
and convenient at times.
In the last few Tribals
you've talked a lot about playing
a fearless game.
So much so that you said
that you fearlessly stood by
your core alliance members.
Now, in the vote that
I was sent home, in your own words,
you said that, "When a cat is
drowning you don't save it."
So, you let me go home.
And in your opening pitch you said that
if the one thing that you could do
was to convince people
that you were nice when really you
were a lying, villainous character.
I've heard you contradict
that in your answers tonight.
You have said that
you are actually nice.
Yeah.
I'm confused, so this is your chance
to clarify what you meant by that.
I came into this game
with the real raw me,
and that is this person that
I feel like I find passion
in selflessly doing things for others.
But in this game where
the prime goal is to make sure
you lie to people and manipulate
just for your selfish gain...
..I feel like I couldn't
just do the raw me
and say that, yeah, I will
selflessly do things for others,
because if I did,
then I would be acting on emotions.
And I feel like in this game,
when you do act on emotion
it ends up doing wrong moves.
And that's the reason why I felt
like I had to be capable of lying
and I had to be capable
of manipulating others.
That is how I'm trying
to explain my story.
(THUNDER CRACKS)
OK. Thanks.
Thanks.
I can't believe it's raining
on the last Tribal Council.
Well, you guys started the game
in the rain.
It looks like you're gonna
finish it in the rain.
Luke, you're up.
(GROANS)
- Alrighty.
- (ALL LAUGH)
Man, it feels like I'm
back on the boat, day one.
I'll start off with you, Tara.
I wanna say congratulations.
55 days, it is
a massive task to get here.
I just think you've played
a good game. You're a good person.
Yeah, I'll just move on to Jeri.
Jericho, my boy!
I had the most memorable moments
throughout the whole game with you,
brother.
As much as people say it
about riding coat-tails,
I feel like we were always
coming together talking about
divide and conquer
and creating conflict,
and so our discussions were quite even.
Obviously we'd go off
and I would bring conversations
about who to get out, maybe more.
But I still believe that you deserve
credit to a lot of those moves.
Alright, sweet.
Alright, Peter. It's your turn.
Oh, no. He's gonna hammer me.
Hey, I'm not gonna blast you. Chill.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
- Congratulations, guys - final two.
- Thanks, Petey.
Tara, I'm gonna start with you.
For a lot of this game,
you were under Locky's wing.
And I want to know a move that you made
during the time under Locky's wing
that you personally contributed to
or influenced.
We got AK out.
It has to go back to when
I went up to you and Ziggy
and Jarrad on the beach at Samatau
and I said, "Let's bring in Tessa.
"Let's bring in her as a number
and get rid of AK."
That was under Locky's wing,
and I remember he was like,
"I don't wanna do it.
I don't wanna do it."
It didn't go forward,
but then another twist happened
with the tribe swap.
I already feel that I gave you guys
enough info about AK to say,
"We've gotta get him out."
That was me coming out with a move.
Jericho, I want you to tell me in
three key words what was your game.
Adaptable. Flexible.
'Adaptable' and 'flexible'
are too similar.
OK, sorry.
OK. Adaptable.
Under the radar.
And deadly.
Cool. Thank you guys so much. I'm
excited to vote and see who wins.
- Thanks, Petey.
- (WHISPERS) Thanks, Pete.
Alright, Henry, you're up.
Namaste, y'all.
Let's finish with a bang, yeah?
- Go for it.
- Alright.
Tara, I want you to saddle up
'cause the barrels are coming.
Jericho, put your seatbelt on
'cause there is turbulence coming.
- Yes.
- (ALL LAUGH)
Alright. Tara, are you ready?
I'm saddled up.
The best thing about Australian Survivor
is that it goes for 55 days.
You get 55 days to build a game.
For me, I came in as a fake
yoga instructor from day one
and built a game around that.
All the way until I got kicked out.
What day did you start playing the game
and how did you start playing the game?
Honestly?
I started playing the game
when Locky went home
and I was on my own two feet.
I used only six days to
make some pretty big moves.
That might have been too late
or not enough for some people,
but that is my honest answer.
I'll just do a little pitch for you,
'cause you're not the best at speaking.
I'm not the best at speaking?
Um... you survived on
your social game to get to the end.
You're sitting there,
and not only sitting there,
you were pivotal in deciding
if Jericho could get to the end.
So, you chose, you kept him alive
and you got him there.
You've basically stated that
you didn't have any moves.
All the jury, all I hear is
"All our big moves put us there."
Maybe she's the smart one saying,
"I'm not gonna make my big moves
"till the final seconds, and then
that's how I'm gonna win this game."
Jericho, I've seen some moves
which in my eyes are inconsistent,
confusing and detrimental
to your game play.
You're talking about these shields.
My understanding is you use
the shield to protect yourself,
you don't get that shield and then
stab it yourself by voting them out.
You did that to shield Sarah
and shield me.
Next thing, you had one of the biggest,
most powerful moments in the game -
you could send a jury member home.
It was a bad move.
One, Tessa basically said she
thought Tara was the weaker player,
yet you still vote her out and yet
you still brought Tara to the end.
So, all I want to know is
do you think you had good moves
that outweigh what I believe the bad
moves were in your game play?
Yeah, I feel like I have to own
all the decisions I make.
I knew that when it comes to the merge
you were working with all these
people that were quality players,
and there was gonna be a point
where every single dangerous player
was going to be knocked out, regardless.
It could have been me at that point,
and so when I started realising
that I was in jeopardy I knew that
I needed to have an escape goat.
It meant that I had to
make sure there was conflict
between two parties.
And as long as there was conflict,
I was basically eating
an invisible popcorn
watching two people battling out.
And that's why I felt like I manoeuvred
through a lot of Tribal Councils
where my name was never written down.
When you're actually on the island
you have to make lies
in order to make sure
you cover yourself.
You have to start thinking
outside of the box.
I decided that I was going to take
that route, make great moves
and see that I can blindside
and do things like lying
and deceiving that I don't normally do.
And I can confidently say that,
yeah, I have your blood on my hands,
and I'm fine with that.
And that's why I still am sitting here,
and I feel like that's why
you're sitting there.
Great answer.
Guys, you got there, you smashed us.
Love you all.
OK, well, jury, you've had your
chance to address Jericho and Tara,
you've heard everything
they've had to say.
You should have enough information
now to decide
who you think most deserves
the title of Sole Survivor
and the half-million
that goes with it.
Now, remember tonight
you are voting for a winner.
For the last time...
..it is time to vote.
Jarrad, you're up.
Tara, I came into this vote tonight
really undecided
and I'm actually quite surprised
at where my vote has ended up.
I hope you win
and I hope my vote gets you there.
I've seen your game over 55 days,
and it was entertaining.
And we did do good moves,
so, goddamn, alright.
I'll go count the votes.
Guys, it's been an incredible season.
You've all played hard and played well.
Whoever wins this game
definitely deserves it.
Now all that's left to do
is read the votes.
But...
..I'm gonna do that
back in Australia.
(ALL EXCLAIM)
No!
- I'll see you guys there.
- Oh, my God!
(ALL EXCLAIM)
Oh, my God.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(CHEERING, APPLAUSE)
(LOUD CHEERING)
Wow.
Wow!
Crazy!
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
Welcome to the finale.
(CHEERING AND WHOOPING)
Alright. OK. Let's get to it.
Look, it has been an incredible
season of twists and turns
and blindsides -
a lot of blindsides.
It was Survivor at its absolute best.
And it's all thanks to you guys.
(CHEERING, APPLAUSE)
Tara, Jericho, you guys
did what 22 others couldn't,
you made it to Day 55.
Congratulations.
OK. So, you made your pitch
to the jury.
And in the final twist of the game,
some say it's the cruellest twist,
but the people that you voted out
and put over there,
they are the ones who have now decided
which of you two
deserves to win this game.
- Tara, you seem nervous.
- Oh, I'm nervous.
- You are?
- Yep.
- I don't speak when I'm nervous.
- (CHUCKLES) OK. Alright.
- This is me really nervous.
- That's you really nervous.
Jericho, what's your gut on this?
Oh, I'm shaking.
But I'm proud of my experience.
I'm proud of my game
and I hope I made Australia proud,
my family proud, the fans proud
and Survivor.
(CHEERING, APPLAUSE)
- Ask me again. Ask me again.
- (LAUGHS)
OK. Alright, guys. Moment of truth.
One of you
is about to be crowned Sole Survivor
and walk away with $500,000.
(CHEERING, APPLAUSE)
- Are you ready?
- Yeah.
OK. Remember,
these are votes for a winner.
Mm-hm.
For the final time,
I'm going to read the votes.
I'm really proud of you.
Whoo.
First vote...
Jericho.
(CHEERING, APPLAUSE)
Tara.
Hmm. Tara.
We're tied.
Two votes Tara, two votes Jericho.
Tara.
Three votes Tara, two votes Jericho.
Jericho.
We are tied again - three votes
Tara, three votes Jericho.
Jericho.
(CHEERING, APPLAUSE)
That's four votes Jericho,
three votes Tara.
Winner of Australian Survivor...
..Jericho!
Jericho is the Sole Survivor!
And he just won $500,000.
Jericho, where are you?
- Jeri!
- WOMAN: There's your money, Jeri.
Here's your cheque -
half a million dollars.
Oh, my God!
(ALL CHEER)
There have been
so many great moments this season.
And we're going to get everyone
out here to talk all about them,
so don't go away.
It's the Survivor Reunion Show.
Bro, you won!
Jericho, he's just a good dude, man.
JERICHO: People think that I'm this
naive, young, innocent angel kid.
But I came into this game
leaving my morals out the door.
Of course I'm going to
take these cookies.
Whether it's lie, cheat and steal,
I was willing to do whatever it takes
to win that Sole Survivor title.
Gonna kill some tribemates.
I'm the brown Cookie Monster
and I'm going to drag someone
with me down to hell. (LAUGHS)
WOMAN: Go, Jeri!
JONATHAN: Wow, Jericho
has some serious skills up there.
Oh!
Jericho is off to a very quick start.
Jericho is trying to find
that inner strength to keep going.
WOMAN: Proud of you, Jeri.
I've grown so much.
And I've made a lot of friends here.
I found a brother in Luke.
I couldn't have done half
of the things I did without him.
This experience
will always be part of me.
It's taught me a lot
and I'm grateful for that.
Oh, man.
Whoo!
(CHEERING, APPLAUSE)
Jericho has just been crowned
the Sole Survivor for 2017
and won $500,000!
Whoo!
Jericho. Firstly, congratulations.
But I want you to be honest with me.
Day one, we're on that barge and the
rain is pissing down, it's dark,
it's apocalyptic, in your own terms,
and everyone else is out there and
they have their best game face on.
Did you think
you'd be sitting here right now?
- Did you think you were going
to win this thing? - No way.
Honestly I looked at everybody
and I was just like, "Holy crap.
I'm honestly against these guys."
Some of them are, like, 6'4"
and I was just like...
..how would I compete against them
in the challenges?
But honestly, I'm still shocked
that I'm still standing here.
I was surprised
at my own capability. So, yeah.
Well, it looked like
you were having a blast out there.
You looked like you were scheming
and laughing all the way to Day 55.
What was it about this game
that you love so much?
Oh, look, I've been watching
Survivor since I was a kid.
And so, being there every day,
I just savoured the moment.
And if it was my last day,
I made sure that it was going to be
the most amazing day.
So, you know, with the Locky experience,
that was, like,
one of my biggest highlight.
I was...
I was just stoked that I was there.
Well, I gotta say
I loved the Locky moment too.
That was pretty...
That was pretty cool.
But one of my favourite things about
your game was the whole cookie saga.
- (LAUGHS)
- OK?
- Show them your tie, Jeri.
- That...
Particularly that moment
when you were standing behind
the tribe just eating those cookies.
That was hilarious.
- Jacqui, did you have any idea?
- Absolutely none.
You had no idea
there was a Cookie Monster?
Absolutely none. Nuh. I couldn't
believe it watching it back.
I just thought, "You little bugger."
Right.
Well, there was one person that you
formed a pretty special bond with...
..Luke.
(LAUGHTER)
Piece of crap.
This was what
I had to put up with all the time.
It was driving me crazy.
Can you guys behave?
Just for a little bit?
No. I love it. It's great.
So, what was it about Luke
that you were drawn to?
Oh, I don't know. He just had that
funny vibe where I was just, like...
He's the guy who wants to create chaos.
And I was like,
"I'm jumping on board with that,"
'cause honestly I was, like,
there's going to be times
where we're going to be too serious
and I need something
where I can just laugh it off.
And the minute he started acting
like, "Nah, let's change it up."
And I was like, "Boom, I'm so in."
It was an instant connection.
Love at first sight.
(LAUGHS)
TARA: Here we go.
Honestly, lifelong friendship hopefully.
Yeah. For sure.
Even though he's in Perth
I'll be visiting to see his kids,
see his wife.
And be like, "Yo, I need a room."
You know what I mean?
And now I know he's making all that
money I might have to charge him.
You know what I mean?
There'll be rent.
Nice.
Tara, you were the only other person
that made it to Day 55.
You came second. But it's no mean
feat coming second in this game.
You played a brilliant social game.
- How proud are you?
- I'm pretty proud.
Like, I feel coming into this tonight,
like, Jeri and I spoke so much
and we kept saying,
like, both of us feel deserving.
So that's where, you know,
at the end of the day,
I'm not shattered, I'm not gutted.
I did this experience,
like, hopefully
not getting out the first day.
So I was pretty stoked that, you know,
I got to experience Day 55 with Jeri.
Now, were you surprised how hard
everyone started playing this game
right from the get-go?
Right from A.K. Yes.
That is correct.
Um, no. I...
I didn't even know how to approach
the whole game play, you know?
I... I guess from the start
I was sort of still asking everyone,
"Like, where's the huts?"
In America... And they're like,
"You have to build them."
And I'm like...
You have to do what now?
So, no...
These guys came out swinging
from day one. So it's a tough game.
It is a tough game.
And there were no shortage
of big players this season.
I mean, there's Henry, Locky, Luke.
I mean, in fact all of you.
You all came out of the gate,
swinging for the fences.
It was great to watch.
I always say go big or go home.
And this season there was one player
who ended up doing both.
Let's take a look.
I came into this game
hoping to play to my strengths,
which was my social game.
- Why not?
- You remind me of my Uncle Mark.
- Do I?
- Yeah, man.
I plan on making an alliance with
every single person in my tribe.
I'm here to play Survivor.
I'm not here to make friends.
I'm playing to win.
My plan is organised chaos.
- What?
- It's a rock.
I want to elevate the stress
and paranoia.
- Oh, I could slap him.
- (CHUCKLES)
Playing a hell of a game, though.
Hell of a game.
He is a very smart player.
I just want to be remembered
as the player that played big.
You're like little puppets. He's the
mastermind and you're the puppets.
(CHEERING, APPLAUSE)
Well, A.K.,
when I look at that footage
I think that's pretty good strategy
to try and befriend everyone.
Why do you think it didn't work?
Um... Well, I feel like it did work.
I mean, I stuck with my best brother
Jarrad from day one, Ziggy.
No.
But I think my problem was I was
going off alone with these people
when they were going out
getting firewood,
when they were finding things
and I was having these one-on-one
conversations with them
where I probably
should have just sat myself
where we were building the shelter
and had these conversations
around people
so it didn't look so suspicious.
OK. Look, I gotta ask. Chicken Idol.
Really?
Hands up.
Who bought the Chicken Idol?
- It's a rock.
- (LAUGHTER)
I wasn't on the same tribe as A.K.
So...
- Ben definitely would have bought it.
- (LAUGHTER)
Oh...
- Ben, that was harsh.
- Yeah. Mate.
It's all good.
Well, A.K., I think it's fair to say
that you put quite a few noses
out of joint early in the game,
but none more so than Tara.
Tara, what was it about A.K.
that just rubbed you the wrong way?
I think it was just
going out too hard at the start.
And, like, you know,
he said, we're trying to build fire
and we're trying to do huts
and he's just, like, scamming
and running around
looking for chicken idols.
So, yeah, I guess...
I mean, I love him but... Now.
But, I mean...
So you guys have had contact
since the game finished?
- Yeah.
- It's cool.
He's, like,
the godfather of my children.
No. No. I was kidding.
Wow. Did I miss something?
- LOCKY: Hey?!
- I'm kidding.
Locky. Locky. Locky, look at me.
No. No. No.
So, I guess you could say it was
just his game play. It scared me.
That's what it was.
It was so powerful and so good
that I was just like,
"Let's just get him."
Well, A.K.,
when we did the tribe swap
and you pulled that Asaga buff,
did you think that was it,
"My game's up"?
Yeah.
I mean, Tara and Anneliese
had been over at Asaga
for probably a week at that point
and, you know,
perception is 90% of reality
and the chances of me making it
through that next Tribal
Council at Asaga were pretty slim.
Luke, how's your wall looking
with A.K.'s head stuffed on it?
Yeah. The only one I didn't get
was Lock. He escaped it.
But, yeah,
it was all about trophies for me.
So, like, the room is full at home.
(LAUGHTER)
Well, A.K.,
you were a master manipulator.
You played a hell of a game.
- Well done.
- Thanks, mate.
(CHEERING, APPLAUSE)
Coming up after the break,
we're going to hear from
the one and only Tarzan.
- And later...
- (CHEERING, APPLAUSE)
And later,
we're going to speak to the player
who made possibly the dumbest move
of the game.
Don't go away.
(SHOUTS)
Australian Survivor has been
the toughest thing I've ever done.
Testing my boundaries, seeing what
type of a man I really was.
JONATHAN: Oh, a huge fall!
That's what this game was about for me.
Mark is furiously trying to get
that kindling to catch.
- No way.
- Stick it in your pocket.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDS)
I just want to be remembered
as the lovable character
who didn't let the game
get in the way of life.
Tarzan, you are just my hero.
Thanks, mate.
Honesty and integrity - look,
it may not win this game for you,
but I just wanted me grandkids
to be proud,
and going, "That's our Pop."
This is a moral dilemma.
To me...
We won! We won!
..that is the duck's nuts
of being a Pop.
You're a rock star, Tarzan.
(APPLAUSE)
Welcome back to the reunion show!
The entire cast of Australian
Survivor season two is here,
including this man, Tarzan.
Hey, mate.
Thank you.
Tarzan,
if social media is any indication,
you were one of the most loved
players in the game.
What's the reaction been like
for you on the street?
Well, mate, I'm not gonna die
not knowing what it was like
to be famous for a day.
(LAUGHTER)
You know, I have had a blast.
There's not one moment I wouldn't
cherish for the rest of my life
and I wouldn't change a thing,
and I suppose at the end of the day,
maybe that's what made me so lovable.
ALL: Awwww.
Thanks, mate! (LAUGHS)
Thanks, guys!
Alright, I want to talk about the Idol.
Yeah.
Now, surely you must have known
that by giving it to Tessa
you put your own game at risk.
Yes, Tessa needed it.
I didn't feel I needed the Idol
until somebody with initials AK
sort of...
..you know, changed a few things.
But he tried.
He was on our side for a minute.
I'm glad you brought that up
because when I...
..when I watched it, I thought,
that's actually quite brilliant.
- You're gonna flip the whole
game on its head. - Yeah.
You're gonna send someone else home,
I think it was gonna be...
- Locky, yeah. I was gonna...
- Great blindside.
Yes.
But then you went and told AK.
- Yeah, I know! (LAUGHS)
- Why?
Well, I think in life,
I've done this before,
if you want to get trust,
you've got to give it.
So in this case, we didn't get it back,
but that was the game
and that was the risk.
Tessa did bring it.
Like, she went on and she kept going.
(APPLAUSE)
Well, look, Tarzan, people may have
viewed you giving the Idol to Tessa
as a bad decision,
but in a game that's 55 days long,
everyone's bound to make
a bad decision or two.
- Yeah.
- Right, Ziggy?
(LAUGHTER)
Oh, Ziggy, I'm just...
(LAUGHS)
OK. Ziggy, seriously, seriously, you
found the biggest power in the game,
- the Super Idol.
- Yeah.
And then you used it to save the
biggest threat in the game, Locky.
- Yeah.
- Thanks, Zig.
Good decision or bad decision?
Well, there was no, like, trust
between Anneliese and I,
so for me to send Locky home who
I thought I'd built some trust with,
to form an alliance with Anneliese,
who I'd already broken trust with,
to me just seemed crazy.
And, I mean,
I was a threat in challenges.
Locky was a threat in challenges.
I thought it was too early
to get rid of him
because I'd be the next target
to be sent home, so...
..I stand by it.
(APPLAUSE)
Alright. Good.
Tessa, Jericho won
a special advantage in the game
and he voted you off the jury.
Bad decision?
Oh, well...
It's hard to go back in time,
isn't it, Jeri?
It was heartbreaking for me.
I'm a huge fan of this game.
I so wanted to have my say
at that final Tribal Council,
but honestly,
we didn't know who was gonna be
in the final two at that stage.
And it's true, if this guy
had been sitting at the end
that I would've made a pitch for him
and that would've been dangerous
on the jury.
Whoo.
- (LAUGHTER)
- Whoo.
(APPLAUSE)
Jacqui.
Jonathan.
OK.
You let Henry hold on to the Idol
that you guys both found.
Do you regret that decision?
Oh, look, there's 23 of us that say
"Would've, could've, should've,
"why didn't I?"
And yeah,
I'm not finished with Henry yet.
(LAUGHS)
Alrighty. Well...
(CHEERING)
- Well, on that note...
- (AUDIENCE MEMBER WOLF WHISTLES)
Coming up after the break,
we're gonna talk to the guy
who probably made the worst decision
of the whole game -
Henry and the Idol
he took home in his pocket.
And later, we'll talk to
the king of the jungle.
Don't go away.
(APPLAUSE)
HENRY: Twisting the whole body.
Twisting that spine.
People think of me
as this blue-eyed,
Zen-loving yoga instructor,
and the truth is, from day one,
I've been in game mode.
(CONTESTANTS CHEER)
JONATHAN: Big launch from Henry!
I've thrown challenges.
Everyone's in sync for Asaga.
Except Henry.
Asaga, losing their steam.
I replanted Idols.
I might look like Jesus
but I'm playing like the devil.
Boom! Yeah!
Yeah!
I don't think anyone could argue
that they played better than me.
If anyone has a hidden Immunity Idol
and they want to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
Henry.
Game up. Snap away.
Henry, the tribe has spoken.
(LAUGHS)
(APPLAUSE)
Welcome back to the
Australian Survivor reunion show.
Henry.
OK, so, in that moment in Tribal
when I ask if someone has an Idol,
I normally give it a moment and I hold,
but with you I just kept holding
and holding and holding,
thinking, "He's gonna play it.
He's gonna play it. He's...
"No, he's not gonna play it."
- Yeah.
- What was going on?
I don't know. I couldn't hear Locky.
He wasn't speaking loud enough.
Yeah, nah, honestly, like,
everyone's, oh,
what a dumb-dumb I am,
but you've got to give credit
to the people
that orchestrated that blindside.
Like, we had no time to scramble.
We had two different kind of little
groups of people coming together in,
like, 30 seconds of this rain
kind of set-up back at camp,
so that was one of the best episodes
I've seen of Survivor,
just how they got that plan
in motion, and I looked like a fool,
but man, it was a good move.
It took six of them. So...
(OTHERS CHEER)
Well, Henry, there is no dispute
you were a dope in that moment.
- But...
- (LAUGHTER)
..you played a hell of a game,
you really did. Well done.
Thank you. Thank you.
Alright, so let's talk about yoga.
How much yoga have you really done?
Yeah, I did one class with...
..my brother-in-law and sister and
bought a book on the plane to Samoa,
and read, like, a chapter.
So, honestly, like...
You just say a couple of words.
- The rest is...
- OK, OK.
Hands up. Who bought the story
that he was a yoga instructor?
Hindsight. Hindsight.
Sarah, really?
I mean, look, I'm as stiff as a board
and I know more than he does in yoga.
There was definitely that suspicion
but I feel for me
I still thought he did yoga.
Like, he is that Zen-loving
that I thought that he was...
..there was some sort of yoga
in his life.
But none at all. He's a labourer.
(LAUGHS)
- Well played. Um...
- Thank you.
On a more serious note, now,
your mother passed away a couple of
weeks before you came into the game.
What did Survivor mean to you and her?
Yeah, so...
She just taught me
all through life to chase my dreams
and one of my dreams has been
to get on Survivor
and obviously she was fine
when I first applied
and then through the application process
became bad and went into palliative care
and I found out I was on
and it was six weeks I think
after she passed away.
So I was in a pretty important time
for my family, the grieving process,
to, you know, kind of process it all.
But, you know, it was that shining light
that we all needed in the family,
so, you know,
I'm the man I am today
because of the last three years
and the game I played then,
so I'm stoked
and I would always have gone out
because that's what Mum would've wanted.
(APPLAUSE)
Now, earlier in the game,
you teamed up with Jacqui
and became a power couple.
Was that intentional?
Um, yeah, it was.
We got along really well and I thought
she was the perfect person
to work with, so yeah,
it was the perfect little pair
to go forward with
and we found an Idol
which kind of solidified it.
My Idol.
- Which... which...
- (LAUGHS)
Which he's now gonna give to me.
Which is now coming to my house.
Want it, Jacqui? You want it?
(APPLAUSE)
- I said I'd give it to her.
- I will use it.
Jac, does that make everything better?
Oh...
(LAUGHS)
I don't think so, but nice try.
Well, look, you weren't the only
couple who got together in the game.
- Let's take a look.
- AUDIENCE: Oooh!
LOCKY: Mark and Sammy...
I don't know what's going on there.
Definitely a bit closer
than everyone else.
JERICHO: That's such a good thing!
Sam. Total babe.
Oh, look, if I met her
on the outside and she was single,
I'd definitely be keen on her.
(LAUGHS)
(APPLAUSE)
(WOLF WHISTLE)
Well, Mark, I think it's fair to say
that your close ties with Sam
ended up damaging your game, but
is there a silver lining to this?
There is.
We've come out and we've had
a great life ever since the game.
And when I was there and I first met Sam
I knew there was something special
about her
and we were close in the game early,
I knew it was gonna be a risk
and we took it anyway,
but we got targeted by the tribe
earlier than I thought, so...
But it was worth it. (LAUGHS)
Awwww. (APPLAUSE)
So you guys are still together?
- Absolutely.
- Nice.
Those are pretty nice words
otherwise. (LAUGHS)
Sam, did you perceive
your relationship with Mark
as a power couple?
Oh...
Not really.
I actually befriended Hen
really early on.
But then something about Mark,
I was just like, "I trust that guy,"
and, I mean, if you were
on an island, man or woman,
and it's freezing cold,
you would choose to snuggle up
to Mark as well.
You know, he pretty much is like a
mattress and a doona all in one,
so it was kind of just
a companionship of trust
and he's someone easy to talk to,
so it was nice to have
that little break away.
So, Sam, did you know that Henry
was trying to throw challenges
to get you out or did you just learn
that from watching the episodes?
I remember on that rafting one,
and I do quite a bit of kayaking.
I was like, "There is something
going on with the left side,"
and my first thought was,
"What is Ben doing?"
(CLAPS)
(LAUGHS)
And I...
There's this, like, photo
from that episode
and I'm looking back with
the dirtiest look at that left side
and I'm like, "Something is going
on," and then that final one
when Henry was successful, we were
talking about that and I just said,
"Henry's effort
looked pretty lacklustre."
It definitely felt like
things were going in slow motion.
Which was true. He was...
He was trying to throw that challenge
by just being confused at the puzzle.
Give credit.
Like, he got his move, so...
He pulled it off. Yep. Gotta give
credit where credit is due.
Well done. Well done, Henry.
- Thank you.
- (APPLAUSE)
Alright. After the break,
we talk to the one and only,
the king of the jungle.
And later,
we get to the bottom of some of
the biggest secrets of the season.
Don't go away.
LUKE: I work in the mining industry.
I'm a driller.
So, the tribe are probably thinking
I've got no skills.
But I've been playing my own game
since day dot.
I'm here to stir the pot.
"Hey, you can't be sitting there,
walking around,
"thinking you're the boss.
"I'm the boss!"
- (LUKE ROARS)
- (SCREAMS)
(BLEEP!)
Gotcha. Gotcha!
I'm lying through my teeth.
I really want Tara to go, man.
She's starting to do my head in, bro.
I told him I was gonna stuff him
and put him up on my wall.
I'm acting, out here.
Bold and the Beautiful.
That's... Get me something on there.
Oh, shit.
I'll save you when you're swimming.
- What else... what else shall we do?
- Yeah.
BOTH: Whoo-hoo!
I'm the king of the jungle, baby.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
The king, baby!
Welcome back to the Australian
Survivor Reunion show.
Jericho has just won
a half a million dollars
and I bet he feels like
a king right now.
But he's not the only royal
on the stage tonight.
I give you...
..Luke, king of the jungle.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Or would you prefer "the boss"?
Or the President or the Mayor.
Or whatever. You know what I mean?
OK. I gotta be honest
with you, Luke.
When I first started watching you,
I thought, "This guy
is really impulsive."
You know, it was just...
You're like Captain Chaos.
Yeah.
But as things went on, your game
really started to come together.
Did you have a plan, coming into this?
Uh... not really.
I'd say, at the start, it was just like
I wanted to be at the top, you know?
So, I wanted to create a ladder.
Uh, and then, obviously,
I linked up with Jeri
So, we were trying to, like,
split people up
and always create drama,
but try to stay out of it.
That was our plan.
Did you know a lot about the game
before you came in?
Were you a student of the game or
were you just learning on the job?
I was learning on the job.
I did, like, a little bit of research,
watched a little bit of YouTube,
and that was about it.
(LAUGHTER)
I applied, got on the show
and gave it a good old crack.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Henry, did you underestimate
this guy, early on?
Big-time. Like, watching it back,
he's one of...
..in my opinion,
the best player out here.
Just, like, in terms of
strategy-based, like...
(APPLAUSE) And just the way we
weren't aware of it. I think...
That's what I tried to do.
I was like, "I'll do yoga,
"make all the moves behind."
But he just did it naturally,
with his personality
and, yeah, he was so good to watch.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Sarah, at what point did you realise,
"This is actually a brilliant player"?
Well, I played a game where I knew I
was gonna be friends with everyone,
so day one, I was making friends
with everyone, except one person,
and it was Luke.
'Cause I was thinking, "This guy is
gonna get sent home straightaway.
"He's crazy. I'm not
getting anywhere near him."
And then he kind of kept staying on
and I was like, "Well, crap -
now I've gotta go align with him,"
and we actually ended up,
dude, working together. Yeah.
But he... he's very impressive
with his strategic street smarts
and, yeah, you can see it on the show.
Well, Luke, I just want to
talk about something here.
Maybe the audience doesn't know,
but when you start this game,
you're allowed five pieces of clothing.
But your wardrobe
seemed to keep growing.
Yeah.
Every time someone was eliminated,
you'd turn up
wearing an item of their clothing.
What was going on there?
(LAUGHTER)
Uh... so...
Pretty much day one, I lost my hat,
I lost my shirt,
and I got a hole in my pants,
and then I found Sam's hat
when she left,
and then it just continued.
I just still wish, uh,
Sarah left her bikini
'cause I was, uh...
- ..I was gonna rock it to Tribal.
- I was taking that with me.
I swear to God, I was gonna maybe
rock it to Tribal, so...
(LAUGHTER AND GROANING)
(APPLAUSE)
Alright, I'm gonna
leave that one alone. Um...
Well, you were clearly
having fun out there,
but you were also playing hard -
so much so that you built yourself
a spy shack.
Let's take a look.
Oh, man, look, you know what?
I'm planning just to mess everyone up.
I just wanna sit in the bush
and be creepin'.
You know, everyone wants to drink water
when they want to make alliances.
I'll be like this, here.
(LAUGHTER)
So, it's not that, like, I... I...
I think the order of elimination...
OK.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
I'm creepin'. Creepin'.
I'm sorry!
(APPLAUSE)
Alright, guys - did anyone know
about the spy shack?
TARA: No.
You knew?
- Yeah.
- Of course.
Yeah. Yeah. 'Cause you
do everything together.
Actually, you're like one person, right?
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Well, Luke, you entertained us
from day one.
What was the public response back home?
Man, the public's been crazy good!
Like, uh, there is
so much love everywhere.
Even within the guys here,
like, when people
were actually struggling...
Like, I don't... I wouldn't say
I struggled at all, you know?
So, when people were doing it hard,
I kinda, like... like tried to
pick people up, you know?
Like, when Tara come across,
I remember, like, whispering,
and I was like, "Do not quit.
"Stay in the game. You're here.
You're still here."
Like, you know?
And then she, like... she burned me.
You know?
(LAUGHTER)
Yeah.
- And, um... Yeah.
- (CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Yeah. There we go.
Alright.
Coming up after the break,
we'll take a look at
some of the incredible moments
from this year's challenges.
And later, we expose
some of the secrets and lies
these guys have told each other.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
JONATHAN: This game is on!
Survivors ready?
Go!
Luke... Asaga just fell in!
Everyone powering ahead.
Go, go, go, left!
Oh, they're gonna lose it
on the side of the ramp!
Aagh!
Locky is a beast in this game.
(GROWLS)
Nothing easy about Survivor.
But, hey, you didn't
come out here for easy.
You came out here to play.
(SCREAMING)
So, play hard.
Watch out for that... Oh!
JONATHAN: Oh, Ziggy!
LOCKY: You're a rock star.
Everyone very focused.
You guys have been up there
for two hours.
(CHEERING)
Really struggling now.
Aaaaaagh!
This is classic Survivor, right here.
Never give up!
Locky is completely naked!
(CHEERING)
(LAUGHS)
(AUDIENCE MEMBER WOLF-WHISTLES)
Welcome back to
the Survivor Reunion Show.
Mark...
Was that a strategy,
to pull down Locky's pants?
It actually was deliberate,
but I was disturbed by it
for that whole challenge.
(LAUGHTER AND APPLAUSE)
Locky, you seemed quite happy
to let your freak flag fly,
but was there...
was there a moment in there
when you thought,
"Maybe I should pull my pants up"?
Nah. Not once.
(LAUGHTER)
I mean, it was fishing gear.
Like, I had to win that,
just to go out and fish.
So, that's the one I wanted,
so a bit of nudity wasn't a problem.
Well, I'm sure the ladies
in the audience
thank you for that decision.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
LOCKY: Jordan?
So, Mark, you and Locky went head
to head on a bunch of challenges.
Who do you think won that battle
in the end?
Oh, Locky got...
..pretty much all of them,
unfortunately.
No, we had a couple of good wrestles.
That first one was a cracker.
And then, uh, I was expecting to
get him in the sumo challenge,
but instead, I got Jarrad,
who was just as ferocious.
So, it was a good battle, though.
And you held your own. Well done.
CONTESTANTS: Yeah!
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Well, Locky, you were a powerhorse.
You ended up winning
three Immunity Challenges in a row.
You were two seconds away from
winning that fourth one.
Does that keep you up at night?
Nah, not at all.
Nah, yeah, every night.
(LAUGHTER)
Um...
- Alright, Michelle...
- Yeah.
OK, so, you beat Locky.
- Yep.
- You beat him by two seconds.
- But you beat him.
- Yes.
And you won a car.
I mean, arguably,
the best Immunity Challenge to win.
I mean, and what a car.
Holden Trailblazer.
(LAUGHTER AND APPLAUSE)
I know what I'm doin'!
You do. Nice plug for
the sponsor there. I like it.
- It's an amazing car, so...
- Great.
I love it.
Great. Well, you won it,
fair and square. Well done.
Thank you.
(APPLAUSE)
Aimee...
I think you had the biggest fall
of the season.
In fact, probably the biggest fall
in Survivor,
certainly that I've ever seen.
Whenever I watch that footage, I cringe.
How is it for you,
when you see that back?
Yeah. Oh, man, I fell so hard.
But I was...
I actually said after it,
"My mum dropped me on the head
a lot when I was a child,
"so I'm just used to it."
(LAUGHTER)
Sorry, Mum.
(APPLAUSE)
Alright. OK.
Well, look, in a game where the object
is to outwit, outplay
and outlast each other,
it was really nice to see
that Aussie mateship
was still at its core.
Let's take a look.
Ah-ha-ha!
JERICHO: When I came into this game,
I didn't think
that I would make genuine friendships.
But Survivor has really surprised me.
I've found probably
my best friends here.
(ALL CHEER)
TARA: When you get thrown into
this game,
you have to build trust,
you've got to build friendship.
You've got to have
that one friend in the game
that you can just say
whatever you want to.
That's what I feel with Locky.
Mum, my best friend, he's hot.
You'll love him.
I'm not breaking up with you, I promise.
- I know. I love ya.
- I know. I love you too.
It's so tough out here,
and it's been really difficult.
- (CRIES) So, that's my mum.
- That's Shirls.
That's the littlest one?
But to go through it with people
who love and support me,
that's something to be grateful for.
Aww! That's gold!
JERICHO: It's really
made me question,
"Are you here for that prizemoney
"or is there more
that's more valuable?"
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Locky, you and Tara seemed to be
tight, very tight, from day one.
Why do you think that was?
Uh, we just, like,
got along, as friends.
I mean, we were on the bottom
a fair bit together
and that just brought us together,
and we've just got the same humour
and everything.
Yeah, and she's a really good friend.
And he's really hot!
(LAUGHTER)
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Well, Tara, in the end,
you had to vote out...
Well, you didn't have to,
but you DID vote out
your best friend
and closest ally in the game.
How hard was that for you?
It was a struggle.
Like, I tried my best
to try and, you know, get around it
but at the end of the day, I had to
do, you know, a good move.
And it was just suckful
that it had to be Locky.
Locky, did you think Tara
would ever turn on you?
No.
(LAUGHTER)
No. I mean, like, I even said
to her, in the game,
I'm like, "Hey, like, you're
probably gonna have to turn on me
"and when you do it,
I'm gonna be super-proud."
But, um, yeah, I didn't see it coming.
Like, she played it pretty well.
And, like, I felt pretty confident
with the challenges,
but, yeah, it stung a little bit,
watching it back.
Did you give her your vote in the end?
I did.
- AUDIENCE: Aw!
- Nice!
(APPLAUSE)
(CHEERING)
Stick around because, after the break,
we're gonna talk to Kristie
and Phoebe from season one
and these guys are gonna come clean
with some of the biggest secrets
of the game.
Don't go away.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Well, I'm sitting here with winner
Kristie and Phoebe from season one.
Kristie, how have you enjoyed
the game play so far this season?
Oh, it's been incredible.
You guys have absolutely killed it.
They took it up to a whole
'nother level.
The twists were great and you took
advantage of every opportunity.
I am so proud.
Nice.
(APPLAUSE)
Phoebe, how would you rate this season?
Oh, I mean, no secret
I'm a Survivor superfan.
And I've gotta say that,
this is, without a doubt, one of
my favourite seasons of all time.
So, well done, guys.
Well, it wouldn't be a good
season of Survivor
without a whole bunch of secrets
and lies.
Let's take a look.
Put your hand up
if you haven't lied in this game.
(LAUGHS)
Yeah. Whatever!
Gentleman in the back there.
I'm a fashion designer
from New York City.
I'm actually a fashion designer,
but in my 16 years in the military
I was a special ops commander.
There's no way I want to let people know
what I was up to in my previous life.
I could be seen as a threat.
HENRY: So we had some jam and sugar
left over.
So sweet.
I'm gonna make sure that
I get all this jam into my belly.
There's, like, nothing left.
Someone's literally put their finger
in there and licked it clean.
Anneliese would have had the jam,
for sure.
Everyone believes Anneliese did it.
That wasn't our intention,
but now I hope I can get away with this.
A Super Idol.
It's a power like I've never seen.
But, before you know it,
you're like kicked out of here
because you've got an advantage.
So, I was gonna lie to my tribe.
I'm not allowed to tell you
exactly what it is.
If I say it, then it's void.
HENRY: I don't think Ziggy's
telling us everything.
I think she's lying.
OK. Quick poll.
Hands up who bought Ziggy's story.
Wow. Really?
(LAUGHTER)
Well, if there was one person
in this game
who was more suited to Survivor,
it was Mark.
But no-one seemed to twig
that he was ex-military.
Mark, was it hard not to
go into full military mode?
It was a long bow to draw to say
I was a fashion designer.
I don't think one person would have
actually believed it.
But it was hard not to explain
such a big part of my life.
Because I think when I explain it
people will understand me
a bit more socially.
So, it was hard not going into
full military mode, yeah.
Jacqui, did you honestly believe
that he was just a fashion designer?
- Oh, that jacket. (LAUGHS)
- It is a nice jacket.
I only got to spoon with him
one night and then she took over.
(LAUGHTER, APPLAUSE)
We'll leave that alone.
Henry. So, you wake up
in the middle of the night.
You're stealing the jam, the sugar.
Was there a moment there
when you thought,
"Maybe I shouldn't be doing this."
Yeah, we just got back
after the Jarrad vote.
And me, Luke and Jerry were like,
"Let's go eat the jam."
Put it on beans. Doing everything.
Ate all that, then in the morning
it was like, oh, having fun.
Then everyone's just blaming Anneliese.
So the next night I'm like,
"Ooh, there's sugar there too."
So I'm like, let's get that into me.
Tipping that out.
Yeah, they can have rice.
That's alright.
Anneliese...
(GIGGLES)
Annaliese...
..why do you think you were framed
as the jam thief?
(LAUGHS)
Um... it could be because
I stare at people
when they have food left
and they're eating,
and that makes them uncomfortable.
But... I guess it had to be
something about my personality
that would make people think
that I ate the jam.
And maybe because I was carrying
the empty jam jar as well.
I'm... I don't know. (LAUGHS)
(APPLAUSE AND LAUGHTER)
Before we finish up,
I want to thank all of you again
for an exceptional season.
Well done.
Henry, what have you learnt
from your time on Survivor?
Oh, that it's the best game ever.
I had the best fun out there.
So, if they go around for season 3,
apply. Anyone can do it.
And play your Idol, right?
Oh, yeah.
Well, Jacqui's decision now.
- Maybe it didn't work.
- Maybe not. Maybe not.
Luke, would you... would you
do it again?
Er, I gotta run it past the wife
I think, yeah.
And the kids, you know.
Yeah, look...
I don't know. Hit me up
in a couple of years, you know?
Ooh.
Jericho.
Any tips for future players?
Ah, have fun out there.
Scheme, lie - do everything...
..with a smile.
With a smile. Exactly.
Well, that is it for season 2
of Australian Survivor.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
55 days, 24 people, one Survivor.
Congratulations, Jericho.
Goodnight!
(TRIUMPHANT MUSIC)
- Thanks, JL.
- Oh, thank you.
Hey.
Well done. You deserve it.